<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
   <original>
      <standard version="FGDC-STD-001-1998">
         <title>Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</title>
      </standard>
   </original>
   <identification dataset="m_3310660_sw_13_1_20110521">
      <title>STRAWBERRY PEAK, SW NAIP DOQQ (3310660) - 2011</title>
      <abstract>
This data set contains imagery from the National Agriculture
Imagery Program (NAIP).  The NAIP program is administered by
USDA FSA and has been established to support two main FSA
strategic goals centered on agricultural production.
These are, increase stewardship of America's natural resources
while enhancing the environment, and to ensure commodities
are procured and distributed effectively and efficiently to
increase food security.  The NAIP program supports these goals by
acquiring and providing orthoimagery that has been collected
during the agricultural growing season in the U.S. The NAIP
orthoimagery is tailored to meet FSA requirements and is a
fundamental tool used to support FSA farm and conservation
programs.  Orthoimagery provides an effective, intuitive
means of communication about farm program administration
between FSA and stakeholders.
New technology and innovation is identified by fostering and
maintaining a relationship with vendors and government
partners, and by keeping pace with the broader geospatial
community.  As a result of these efforts the NAIP program
provides three main products: DOQQ tiles,
Compressed County Mosaics (CCM), and Seamline shape files
The Contract specifications for NAIP imagery have changed
over time reflecting agency requirements and improving
technologies.  These changes include image resolution,
horizontal accuracy, coverage area, and number of bands.
In general, flying seasons are established by FSA and are
targeted for peak crop growing conditions.  The NAIP
acquisition cycle is based on a minimum 3 year refresh of base
ortho imagery.  The tiling format of the NAIP imagery is based
on a 3.75' x 3.75' quarter quadrangle with a 300 pixel buffer
on all four sides.  NAIP quarter quads are formatted to the UTM
coordinate system using the North American Datum of 1983.
NAIP imagery may contain as much as 10% cloud cover per tile.
</abstract>
      <purpose>
NAIP imagery is available for distribution within 60 days
of the end of a flying season and is intended to provide current
information of agricultural conditions in support of USDA farm
programs. For USDA Farm Service Agency, the 1 meter and 1/2 meter
GSD product provides an orthoimage base for Common Land Unit
boundaries and other data sets.  The 1 meter and 1/2 meter NAIP
imagery is generally acquired in projects covering full states in
cooperation with state government and other federal agencies that
use the imagery for a variety of purposes including land use
planning and natural resource assessment.  The NAIP is also used
for disaster response.  While suitable for a variety of uses,
prior to 2007 the 2 meter GSD NAIP imagery was primarily intended
to assess "crop condition and compliance" to USDA farm program
conditions. The 2 meter imagery was generally acquired only
for agricultural areas within state projects.
</purpose>
      <supplinfo>Images are available for download in two formats.  GeoTiff four band image and MrSid RGB.</supplinfo>
      <contact role="point-contact" ref="d1e152"/>
      <citation role="identify" ref="d1e10"/>
      <time>
         <single date="2011-05-21"/>
         <current>Ground Condition</current>
      </time>
      <themes>
         <theme thesaurus="None">
            <term>farming</term>
            <term>Digital Ortho rectified Image</term>
            <term>Ortho Rectification</term>
            <term>Quarter Quadrangle</term>
            <term>NAIP</term>
            <term>Aerial Compliance</term>
            <term>Compliance</term>
         </theme>
      </themes>
      <places>
         <place thesaurus="Geographic Names Information System">
            <term>NM</term>
            <term>Sierra</term>
            <term>35051</term>
            <term>NM051</term>
            <term>SIERRA CO NM FSA</term>
            <term>3310660</term>
            <term>STRAWBERRY PEAK, SW</term>
            <term>STRAWBERRY PEAK</term>
         </place>
      </places>
      <browse>
         <filename>None</filename>
         <description>None</description>
         <filetype>None</filetype>
      </browse>
      <native>Unknown</native>
   </identification>
   <constraints>
      <access type="data">There are no limitations for access.</access>
      <use type="data">
None.  The USDA-FSA Aerial Photography Field office
asks to be credited in derived products.
</use>
   </constraints>
   <spatial>
      <west>-106.628261111</west>
      <east>-106.559172222</east>
      <south>32.9963527778</south>
      <north>33.0661416667</north>
      <indspref>SIERRA</indspref>
      <sprefs>
         <spref type="datum">
            <code>4269</code>
            <authority>EPSG</authority>
            <onlineref>http://www.epsg-registry.org/export.htm?gml=urn:ogc:def:crs:EPSG::4269</onlineref>
            <title>North American Datum of 1983</title>
         </spref>
         <spref type="ellipsoid">
            <code>7019</code>
            <authority>EPSG</authority>
            <onlineref>http://www.epsg-registry.org/export.htm?gml=urn:ogc:def:ellipsoid:EPSG::7019</onlineref>
            <title>Geodetic Reference System 80 (GRS 80)</title>
         </spref>
         <spref type="gridsys">
            <code>26713</code>
            <authority>EPSG</authority>
            <onlineref>http://www.epsg-registry.org/export.htm?gml=urn:ogc:def:crs:EPSG::26713</onlineref>
            <title>Universal Transverse Mercator, 13</title>
         </spref>
      </sprefs>
      <raster type="Pixel" cval="unsigned eight-bit integer">
         <rows>6570</rows>
         <columns>7640</columns>
      </raster>
   </spatial>
   <quality>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Irregular</update>
      <logical>
NAIP 3.75 minute tile file names are based
on the USGS quadrangle naming convention.
</logical>
      <completeness>None</completeness>
      <qual type="horizontal">
         <report>
NAIP horizontal accuracy specifications have evolved over
the life of the program.  From 2003 to 2004 the
specifications were as follows: 1-meter GSD imagery was
to match within 3-meters, and 2-meter GSD to match within 10
meters of reference imagery.  For 2005 the 1-meter GSD
specification was changed to 5 meters matching the reference
imagery.  In 2006 a pilot project was performed using true
ground specifications rather than reference imagery.  All
states used the same specifications as 2005 except Utah,
which required a match of +/- 6 meters to true ground.
In 2007 all specifications were the same as 2006 except
Arizona used true ground specifications and all other states
used reference imagery.  In 2008 and subsequent years
no 2-meter GSD imagery was acquired and all specifications
were the same as 2007 except approximately half of the
states acquired used true ground specifications and the
other half used reference imagery.  The 2008 states that
used absolute ground control where; Indiana, Minnesota,
New Hampshire, North Carolina, Texas, Vermont, and Virginia.
From 2009 to present all NAIP imagery acquisitions used
the +/- 6 meters to ground specification.
</report>
      </qual>
   </quality>
   <lineage>
      <step id="1">
         <description>
Digital imagery was collected at a nominal GSD of 1.0m

using three Cessna 441 aircrafts flying at an average

flight height of 9052m AGL. N14NW, N16NW flew with

Leica Geosystem's ADS80/SH82 digital sensors sn30017 &amp;

sn30034 both with firmware 3.15. N911PJ flew with Leica

Geosystem's ADS40/SH52 digital sensor sn30014 with

firmware v2.14. Each sensor collected 11 image bands.

PanF27A,PanF02A and PanB14A panchromatic bands with a

spectral range of 465-676nm. RedN00a and RedB16a with a

spectral range of 604-664nm. GrnN00a and GrnB16a with a

spectral range of 533-587nm. BluN00a and BluB16a with a

spectral range of 420-492nm and Near-infrared bands

NirN00a and NirB16a with a spectral range of 833-920nm.

The CCD arrays have a pixel size of 6.5 microns in a

12000x1 format. Both the CCD's and the A/D convertors

have a dynamic range of 12bits. The data is stored in

16bit format. The ADS is a push-broom sensor and the

ground footprint of the imagery at NAIP scale is 12km

wide by the length flightline. The maximum flightline

length is limited to approximately 240km.

The factory calibrations and IMU alignments for each

sensor (sn30017 8/6/2009, sn30014 5/15/2008 and

sn30034 12/7/2007) were tested and verified by in-situ

test flights before the start of the project.

The Leica ADS Flight Planning and Evaluation Software

(FPES) is used to develop the flight acquisition plans.

Flight acquisition sub blocks are designed first to

define the GNSS base station logistics, and to break

the project up into manageable acquisition units. The

flight acquisition sub blocks are designed based on

the specified acquisition season, native UTM zone of

the DOQQs, flight line length limitations (to ensure

sufficient performance of the IMU solution) as well

as air traffic restrictions in the area. Once the sub

blocks have been delineated they are brought into FPES

for flight line design. The design parameters used in

FPES will be 30% lateral overlap and 1.0m resolution.

The flight lines have been designed with a north/south

orientation. The design takes into account the

latitude of the state, which affects line spacing due

to convergence as well as the terrain. SRTM elevation

data is used in the FPES design to ensure the 1m GSD

is achieved over all types of terrain.

The raw data was downloaded from the sensors after

each flight using Leica XPro software. The imagery was

then georeferenced using the 200Hz GPS/INS data

creating an exterior orientation for each scan line

(x/y/z/o/p/k). Technicians precisely measured tie

points in 3 bands/looks (Back/Nadir/Forward) for each

line using Leica Xpro software. The resulting point

data and exterior orientation data were used to

perform a full bundle adjustment with ORIMA software.

Blunders were removed, and additional tie points

measured in weak areas to ensure a robust solution.

Once the point data was clean and point coverage was

acceptable, photo-identifiable GPS-surveyed ground

control points were introduced into the block

adjustment. The bundle adjustment process produces

revised exterior orientation data for the sensor with

GPS/INS, datum, and sensor calibration errors modeled

and removed. Using the revised exterior orientation

from the bundle adjustment, orthorectified image

strips were created with Xpro software and the May

2011 USGS 10m NED DEM. The Xpro orthorectification

software applies an atmospheric-BRDF radiometric

correction to the imagery. This correction compensates

for atmospheric absorption, solar illumination angle

and bi-directional reflectance. The orthorectified

strips were then overlaid with each other and the

ground control to check accuracy. Once the accuracy of

the orthorectified image strips were validated the

strips were then imported into Inpho's OrthoVista 4.5

package which was used for the final radiometric

balance, mosaic, and DOQQ sheet creation. The final

DOQQ sheets, with a 300m buffer and a ground pixel

resolution of 1m were then combined and compressed to

create the county wide CCMs.
</description>
         <rundate date="2013-05-09"/>
      </step>
   </lineage>
   <attributes>
      <overview>32-bit pixels, 4 band color(RGBIR) values 0 - 255</overview>
      <eacite>None</eacite>
   </attributes>
   <metadata>
      <contact role="point-contact" ref="d1e398"/>
      <pubdate date="2013-09-20"/>
   </metadata>
   <contacts>
      <contact id="d1e152">
         <organization>
            <name>Aerial Photography Field Office (APFO)</name>
         </organization>
         <address type="mailing and physical address">
            <addr>2222 West 2300 South</addr>
            <city>Salt Lake City</city>
            <state>Utah</state>
            <postal>84119-2020</postal>
            <country>USA</country>
         </address>
         <voice>801-844-2922</voice>
         <fax>801-956-3653</fax>
         <email>apfo.sales@slc.usda.gov</email>
      </contact>
      <contact id="d1e398">
         <position>Clearinghouse Manager</position>
         <organization>
            <name>Earth Data Analysis Center</name>
         </organization>
         <address type="mailing and physical address">
            <addr>MSC01 1110</addr>
            <addr>1 University of New Mexico</addr>
            <city>Albuquerque</city>
            <state>NM</state>
            <postal>87131-0001</postal>
            <country>USA</country>
         </address>
         <voice>505-277-3622 ext. 230</voice>
         <fax>505-277-3614</fax>
         <email>clearinghouse@edac.unm.edu</email>
         <hours>0800 - 1700 MT, M-F -7 hours GMT</hours>
      </contact>
   </contacts>
   <citations>
      <citation id="d1e10">
         <title>STRAWBERRY PEAK, SW NAIP DOQQ (3310660) - 2011</title>
         <origin>USDA-FSA-APFO Aerial Photography Field Office</origin>
         <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
         <publication>
            <pubdate date="2013-05-09"/>
            <place>Salt Lake City, Utah</place>
            <publisher>USDA-FSA-APFO Aerial Photography Field Office</publisher>
         </publication>
      </citation>
      <citation id="d1e233">
         <title>STRAWBERRY PEAK, SW</title>
         <origin>USDA-FSA-APFO Aerial Photography Field Office</origin>
         <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
         <publication>
            <pubdate date="2013-05-09"/>
         </publication>
      </citation>
   </citations>
   <sources>
      <source id="d5e2" type="lineage">
         <type>Unknown</type>
         <alias>Georectifed Image</alias>
         <contribution>Digital Georectifed Image.</contribution>
         <current>Aerial Photography Date for aerial photo source.</current>
         <srcdate>
            <single date="2011-05-21"/>
         </srcdate>
         <citation ref="d1e233"/>
      </source>
   </sources>
</metadata>
